

# **BENJAMIN ROSZIPAL**

Ing. BSc, MMS, RN

### contact benjamin@roszipal.at +43 664 8677961

1/2

#### **PROFIL**

I'm Benjamin, once a pro at band-aids and ambulances, now a maestro of tech and learning. Think of me as the nurse who plugged into the Matrix and found a way to make education as exciting as a heart-pounding rescue. With my unique blend of medical expertise and tech wizardry, I'm here to bridge the gap between healthcare and innovation, bringing about a revolution and inspire minds.

### **EDUCATION**

2020 - 2023	Master of Medical Simulation @ MedUniGraz simulation education in nursing
2018 - 2021	Nursing and Health Sciences @ UAS St. Poelten GmbH preclinical care & simulation
2018 - 2018	Practitioner in Medical Simulation @ MedUniGraz didactics in emergency medical services
2017 - 2018	Paramedic @ Austrian Red Cross emergency medical services
2015 - 2016	Emergency Medical Technician (EMT) @ Austrian Red Cross emergency medical services
2010 - 2015	Advanced Technical Institute @ HTL Wiener Neustadt sustainability & technology

#### **COMPETENCES**

facilitator, trainer, project manager, teamworker, leader, sustainability steward, budgetand finance planer, customer manager, marketer

# **BENJAMIN ROSZIPAL**

Ing. BSc, MMS, RN

#### CONTACT

benjamin@roszipal.at +43 664 8677961

2/2

#### **EXPERIENCES**

2023 - now	Master's Thesis Supervisor @ UAS Wiener Neustadt GmbH healthcare informatics & education
2020 - now	Instructor @ AMLS Austria & AHA trainee examination & didactic concepts
2022 - now	Educator @ PHTLS Austria trainee examination & didactic concepts
2022 - now	Trainer @ KAGES Simulation Center Graz non-technical skills & simulation
2022 - now	Researcher & Lecturer @ UAS St. Poelten GmbH nursing & health studies
2022 - now	Learning Specialist @ XRCONSOLE GmbH user-journey & pedagogical concepts
2020 - 2022	Head of Institute @ SIM CAMPUS GmbH emergency, crisis and catastrophy simulation

#### **REFERENCES**

In recent years, I have engaged in a wide range of projects, spanning from hands-on training experiences in virtual reality to intricate multi-user training sessions in mixed reality. As a healthcare professional, I consistently strive to leverage my expertise as a nurse, along with my roles as a trainer, educator, and simulation specialist. Throughout my work, my primary emphasis is on tailoring the user experience for individuals, developing learning objectives, and establishing effective feedback mechanisms.